I was dreaming just now,
and I dreamt of an eye.
Now, I forget, I wonder...
Who am I?
Mom, Dad, where are you?!
That dream...
I was up high in the sky.
Falling, into a red sea.
And then, that eye...
...
I'm up high in the sky.
But this time, I'm not falling.
Well, let's go.
Towers are rising from the clouds.
Wizards play with strings and wings.
They watch the skies, where no bird flies.
I once asked the wizards why the birds don't fly.
And they said: because of the bells' cry.
And I remember now, that indeed it was the bells, that had woken me up.
The bells that had shown me this sky.
But the bells are brittle, and a breeze could make them fall.
And the towers are tall, so I give the wizards my thanks,
and all I did was continue on.
The bells are tolling again.
Tolling again in the distance.
And the bells are telling me again, that only they hold the answers.
And I know, that they speak the truth.
I was taught by the wizards that words reveal the world.
For example, they taught me to See.
See that there are mountains in the wind.
See the flower forests that grow atop them.
And See all that is good, and See all that is bad.
I found myself under large petals,
and have rested here for years.
I befriended the bugs, and found in them my peers.
I was taught by the bugs,
that wizards are made of wisps,
and wisps are made of spores.
I was also taught by the bugs,
that left is left, and right is right.
Oh, how beautiful it is to know the world.
The bugs teach me everything I need to know.
Hours pass, years pass, I've lost count...
But the bugs say that they know my name.
Yet they never teach it to me.
And when I ask, they say that they need not teach,
the things that I already know.
And that I need not feel bad, for knowing what I am.
But this time I'll sneak away, sneak away to the bells.
For the bugs must be lying, for I know not my name.
I hear the bells tolling in these tunnels.
The bugs told me to never ever enter here.
But I don't believe their lies, I ignore their advice.
Instead, I look what lies deeper inside.
I walk and I walk and I walk, I cannot see the sky any more.
These tunnels are warm.
The warmth guides me deeper, it lulls me to sleep.
I stop walking, I sit down, and...
But the bells toll again, wake me up again,
and remind me that I must not sleep.
I go left, I go right, but there is no bell in sight.
But still, I can hear the bells. Why can't I find them?
Did I do something wrong?
Did I anger the bells?
I just want to know my name, have a place to belong...
But the bells told me I am doing great.
And that I need to keep walking on.
But the bells, but the bugs,
they don't want me to See myself.
I turn around, I'm sad,
ignoring the bugs, was that bad?
I wander through the tunnels.
I go right, I go left, and finally,
brighter light enters my sight.
I go back to the bugs, I want to apologize,
but they don't crawl here any more.
I don't know how long I have been walking.
There's only my tummy to tell the time.
And a single cactus lasts me a long, long, while.
Now, ruins lie before me.
The bells do not like these ruins.
Just like the bugs do not like the bells.
And again, I decide to ignore both, and step inside.
Hey, you!
Look up, look up into the sky!
Look me in the eye!
Splendid! Our gazes finally meet.
Who... what...
What are you?!
I am your guide, child.
My... guide?
Look at me, See me, take yourself into me.
I will reveal your purpose.
No, no, no... Eye, you're scary...
Please, please, let me go!
It is not quite time to explain what it is that you see.
You need only know that you are Me.
And that I am You?
Yes, and that You are me.
Listen, child.
Dedicate Yourself to Me, and all will become clear.
I shall give you one simple request.
You must Remember who You are.
And Whom You love.
See... all the Angels have gone away to Fight.
Fly, Child, fly down quickly and Join their Strife.
Lest You will gnaw at Yourself and Forget,
The Meaning Of Your Life.
So this Eye, too, knows who I am...
And the Eye, too, doesn't tell me.
But if the Eye is Me, shouldn't I know too?
My head hurts...
But I, Eye, we made a promise.
If I do as it says, will I remember?
But I cannot fly.
And the bells toll in the distance, away from the Eye, I.
Who to trust? Who to follow?
Are Its words a trick? Is it the bells who are wrong?
I don't know, I don't know, I don't know!
Well, let's go.
I want to see more, here, first.
I did not see everything yet.
I want to See everything.
No, I have to See everything.
Let's go through this gate, and...
are those houses in the distance?
Will there be friends that know my name?
Walking through a large gate, the bells welcome me.
But there is no one left,
it's just empty houses, crumbled, nearly gone.
I just walk, and walk, and walk.
If only there was anyone here...
My feet hurt from all of this walking...
My stomach growls, but I'm tired of these cacti.
Why did I wake up to these islands?
I just want to be someplace nice.
For now, let's just find a place to rest.
I walk into a house. No one lives here.
But there are all kinds of things here.
Useful things, fun things...
But first, let's just take a nap...
The bells toll again.
There is food in this house.
Food so much more yummy than the cactus I've been eating.
I want to take all of it with me,
but I can't carry all of this.
I'm sad again.
I kick a box.
And then, I head out.
I walk around the town some more.
In the center, there is a large tower.
On top of it, a large statue.
Who could that be?
It looks like a king.
Should I just go into that tower?
...
Yes, I Must Go into that tower.
These plants, this heat...
It feels just like before.
I want to go up, but the stairs only go down.
But that doesn't really matter.
For some reason, it feels like what's down here is important.
I just have to follow this feeling.
The rooms change, this one is red, this one is white,
this one is black, this one is yellow...
It's all so pretty.
I keep going down. Further down.
There are some puddles, but it's not water.
I know I Must Not touch them.
Drip...
Drip... Drip...
Drip... Drip... Drip...
Ripples, circles, waves.
But I Must Not touch them.
I sit next to a puddle.
And I look at my reflection.
Do I really look like this?
No, the puddle must be lying.
I Must Not touch it, so I stand up, and keep walking.
Suddenly, a storm.
Below the tower, a strong wind blows sand around.
The sand hurts my face, but I have to go down.
Further down, further down. Even further down.
But now, the only way down is to jump.
It's only a small distance, but it's scary!
I jump..
I jump...
...and land.
But, this wind is so strong...
I tumble to the edge.
I tumble off the edge.
Bye-bye...
Venerable lady... we did it.
At last, the surface.
To have finally reached up here...
These lands are always so much more perilous than they seem.
What dangers will this grove hold?
You did well, child.
Your journey is almost to an end.
Do not falter in its final steps.
I only did well because I didn't run into that beast this time.
It was nothing but a stroke of luck.
Child, do not concern yourself with such trivialities.
We are up here now.
You ought to feel a sense of pride for this.
You are right, my lady.
Soon, I will finally reach the Azachon.
Venerable lady, I must confess.
Speak your heart, child.
The stream stirs so silently...
The springs bubble with such delight...
The stars wax and wane, and the sky waves and wanders...
I see such beauty in this land.
Does that surprise you?
Did you not expect beauty, here in the cosmic midst?
I don't know.
It's just... the things they tell back home, they're different.
Nonetheless, they are true.
Beauty to one is horror to another.
Then, what does that say about me?
One who finds such beauty in the defiled?
I'm aware of its evils, and the taint that stains its sky...
But I'm still inclined to love, somehow.
It's all a matter of perception.
Only a right view may penetrate this illusion.
Then do I simply lack wisdom?
Oh, dear, I'd never accuse you thereof!
But indeed, you do lack wisdom.
...
Incident: the disruptor.
And the father said:
For as long as you have known the girl,
He has been amongst you, and He has prayed for you;
For as long as you have seen the stars, He has ruled them.
The father commanded his servants to embalm the girl.
To baptize her in milk, and to offer her to the stars, faraway.
And then her brother wept, crying:
I won't let the stars steal her away, she is ours forever!
This disappointed the father.
He told him:
She will return with the King when the time is nigh.
When from the stars He descends.
And when He takes our throne once more.
With the King, we walk the world eternal.
The father waved his hand, watched the sky, and made disappear all the threads.
It was day; only the brightest stars were visible.
He continued:
This is our kingdom, my child.
Whatever may disappear is never gone, such is the sky.
Record: the last communion.
And the father said:
The Day awaits us.
The holy rite of the King and Queen will soon commence.
I hereby urge you, who comprise the Kingdom under the sacred Crown,
Unite!
Earth and Sky have settled,
the stars have aligned to open the path to quintessence.
We shall abandon our dwellings, and delve under the waters:
for the Great Cathedral will house the rite,
tomorrow at the time of the solstice.
Fate has it that you will all arrive tomorrow,
for the day is our destiny:
We all have been chosen.
We all must choose to embrace it.
(There are no further records.)
To whom it may concern,
We have heard some Brothers express doubts recently.
Hearing this fills me with profound sadness.
But, while it goes without saying, remember your Masters' teachings.
Surely, you are aware of the consequences of denouncing the League in this manner.
For eons, we have upheld tradition, awaiting this moment.
Thousands of our ancestors did not live to see this glorious day,
but our patience has been rewarded at last.
We shall welcome the herald of a new era in twenty-seven days.
I must emphasize the importance of upholding tradition henceforth.
Only by following the past can we guarantee success.
As tradition prescribes, we shall welcome all who wish to see His face.
But to the Brothers who still harbor doubt, I say this:
Come!
After seeing Him with your own eyes,
you shall surely be convinced he is our King.
The Stars have guided us to this moment.
Hereafter, the Stars shall continue to guide us.
Even if we cannot see them, we shall follow them.
When the sky is obscured, consult quintessence.
If ever you are in doubt, rely on tradition.
Finally, we will be restructuring certain ranks within the League.
If you believe your lineage may be affected, please visit us.
To minimize danger to your lineage, we recommend leaving your disciples at your hives.
We wish you prosperous research.
Signed, the League.
[RANDOMPOS] Spores. [RANDOMPOS]
[RANDOMPOS] Fetid. [RANDOMPOS]
[RANDOMPOS] Tranquil. [RANDOMPOS]
[RANDOMPOS] Nervous. [RANDOMPOS]
[RANDOMPOS] Nerves. [RANDOMPOS]
That accursed Eye...
[RANDOMPOS] Mycelium. [RANDOMPOS]
[RANDOMPOS] Unmoving. [RANDOMPOS]
[RANDOMPOS] White. [RANDOMPOS]
[RANDOMPOS] Humid. [RANDOMPOS]
[RANDOMPOS] Gloom. [RANDOMPOS]
[RANDOMPOS] Murky. [RANDOMPOS]
...should not be...
[RANDOMPOS] Hyphae. [RANDOMPOS]
[RANDOMPOS] Lethargy. [RANDOMPOS]
[RANDOMPOS] Sightless. [RANDOMPOS]
[RANDOMPOS] Mud. [RANDOMPOS]
[RANDOMPOS] Stale. [RANDOMPOS]
[RANDOMPOS] Noise. [RANDOMPOS]
[RANDOMPOS] Tendrils. [RANDOMPOS]
[RANDOMPOS] Lichen. [RANDOMPOS]
[RANDOMPOS] Mold. [RANDOMPOS]
...trusted.
[RANDOMPOS] Vibrations. [RANDOMPOS]
[RANDOMPOS] Unfeeling. [RANDOMPOS]
[RANDOMPOS] Unmoving. [RANDOMPOS]
[RANDOMPOS] Unthinking. [RANDOMPOS]
[RANDOMPOS] Breeze. [RANDOMPOS]
The angels...
[RANDOMPOS] Moisture. [RANDOMPOS]
[RANDOMPOS] Impulse. [RANDOMPOS]
[RANDOMPOS] Growth. [RANDOMPOS]
...should be-
Should Be Treasured.
[RANDOMPOS] Influence. [RANDOMPOS]
[RANDOMPOS] Mute. [RANDOMPOS]
[RANDOMPOS] Filaments. [RANDOMPOS]
[RANDOMPOS] Voice. [RANDOMPOS]
[RANDOMPOS] Evil. [RANDOMPOS]
Don't listen-
Don't Listen To These Aimless Thoughts.
They Are Unworthy.
Can You Not See?
[RANDOMPOS] Roots. [RANDOMPOS]
[RANDOMPOS] Anguish. [RANDOMPOS]
[RANDOMPOS] Mush. [RANDOMPOS]
[RANDOMPOS] Slime. [RANDOMPOS]
I Shall Guide You To Your Destination.
Do You See That Tree?
[RANDOMPOS] Pile. [RANDOMPOS]
[RANDOMPOS] Snow. [RANDOMPOS]
[RANDOMPOS] Soot. [RANDOMPOS]
[RANDOMPOS] Pain. [RANDOMPOS]
The Angels Have Protected You.
From What These Beings Once Were.
Don't-
Pay Them No Heed.
[RANDOMPOS] Stagnation. [RANDOMPOS]
[RANDOMPOS] Rot. [RANDOMPOS]
The Azachon...
[RANDOMPOS] Mycelium. [RANDOMPOS]
[RANDOMPOS] Nerves. [RANDOMPOS]
[RANDOMPOS] Nervous. [RANDOMPOS]
[RANDOMPOS] Tranquil. [RANDOMPOS]
[RANDOMPOS] Fetid. [RANDOMPOS]
[RANDOMPOS] Spores. [RANDOMPOS]
...is a monster.
Please Proceed.
Lest You Become Like Them.
Allow Us To Explain.
Those Who Disrespect Us Must Be Eradicated.
We Are Harmony, Sense, Order.
We Created Order In Form, "Space".
We Created Order In Flow, "Time".
Without Our Laws, Everything Will Revert To Chaos.
Without These Lands, Existence Loses All Value.
But They Defy Us.
But They Desire The Opposite.
They Don't See The Beauty Of Our Laws.
They Consider These Laws "Shackles" Instead.
Their Chaos Is Seeping Into These Lands.
Their Kings' Assault Is Eroding These Lands.
If These Lands Get Reduced To Naught,
If The Pillars On Which The Laws Are Written Are But Rubble,
The Cosmos Will Suffer Everywhere And Alltime.
And While Unfortunate, We Have Become Unable To Stop Them.
The Foot Has Already Been All But Destroyed.
Nothing But An Indistinct Mist Remains.
The Peak Won't Survive For Much Longer.
Nothing We Do Seems To Affect Them.
Their Final Assault Is Already In Motion.
You. We Need You.
You Cannot See It From Here, But See The Surface.
A Land Without Form, Distorted By Impression.
A Land Without Flow, Distorted By Emotion.
An Unnavigable Realm Shaped By Vague Concepts.
And They Want To Rid It Of Its Last Bastions Of Order.
I Hope You Understand Our Plight.
We Must Uphold Our Laws.
But You...
Why Visit These Barren Wastes?
There Is Nothing Here.
There Is But Wasted Time.
Exert Your Efforts Elsewhere.
We Do Not See The Need For You To Visit Here.
For You Will Not Remember Here.
Do You See Those Rock Formations To Your Right?
Do You See The Buildings On Top?
You Shall Go There Instead.
You Shall Help Our Fight There Instead.
Phew.
This stupid place.
Ever since I fell, everything has been so hectic.
That stupid Eye should've just given me wings!
The only reason I'm still alive is pure luck.
Come on, no one could survive such a fall!
But the trees caught me, I only had a few bruises, and that's that.
I'm glad I've found this little area.
The endless supply of water flowing through these gorges...
The gentle breeze between the cliffs swaying the vines...
It's beautiful.
And I can actually... relax here.
I know I shouldn't let my guard down though.
With all the beasts up there and whatnot.
Not to mention the Eye's incessant demands.
But here, I can finally take a breather...
Still, it really messes with me.
Who am I? What is this place?
This sky has no sun... but it feels like it should.
There is just no sense of time here.
And having to be on my guard, always, is so taxing.
But in these ravines, I can hardly see the sky at all.
Without that eerie twilight in my view...
Without the beasts that roam around...
Let's take a nap...
Why do I always forget dreams?
I feel like this one was important.
Funny how that works.
Well then. Well now.
Let's see if I can Remember anything around these parts.
Honored Lord of the Sanctuary, the Red Bell has rung.
Honored Lord of the Sanctuary, the King has perished.
Honored Lord of the Sanctuary, teach us Death.
Honored Lord of the Sanctuary, teach us Birth.
Honored Brothers, it was set in the Stars, was it not?
That on this accursed Day, I were to teach you Death.
Soon, Honored Brothers, shall the Sky shatter;
Soon, Honored Brothers, shall the Water whiten;
And soon, Honored Brothers, shall Silence befall the Sanctuary.
We w█▓▒▒▓▒ ▓▓██▓█ (We w█▓▒▒▓▒ ▓▓██▓█)
Since all Things are Omnipresent,
cultivate the Perception of the Omnipresent.
You shall humbly accept the star-gourd.
I ▓█▓▓▓██ ▓██▓▓ ▒▓▓▒▓██
Since They are possessed of Desire,
cultivate the Perception of Desire.
You shall humbly accept the blood-gourd.
Th█▓▓▒ ▒▓█▓
Since They are set in the Stars,
cultivate the Perception of the Stars.
You shall graciously accept the star-gourd.
Y▓▒▓█████ ▓▓ ▒▓▓█▓▓▓
Since Death is the Destined,
cultivate the Perception of Death.
You shall graciously accept the blood-gourd.
██▓▒▓▓▓ ██▓▓
Honored Lord of the Sanctuary, I submit. (Honored Lord of the Sanctuary, I submit.)
At last, the Sanctuary has almost returned to Silence.
My time has come too.
The time to return to the crimson egg.
The time to return to Silence.
Until the Bell shall toll again.
Be quiet, please.
They
They are...
...sleeping.
First, Decay.
The Province in Ruin;
Where sacrifice shall make mind and soul abandon the body.
Second, and beneath, Purification.
The Province in Darkness;
Where pain and pleasure both shall cleanse the soul of sin.
Third, and beyond the gates, Awakening.
The Province in Flames;
Where the light of inferno shall show the mind its truth.
Fourth, and deep below, Hierogamy.
The Province in deepest Starlight;
Where the essences coalesce, and the triad shall become one.
Earth and Sky have collided, their sacred milk fills the bath.
Beware, and adhere to the acts.
Act 1: You shall not bathe in the quintessence.
Act 2: You shall not interfere with or communicate with those on the other side of the quintessence.
Act 3: You shall not show your bare face to the quintessence.
Act 4: You shall not speak to the quintessence.
Act 5: You shall not listen to the quintessence.
Act 6: You shall not lay your eyes upon the quintessence.
Act 7: You shall not tell any heretics or uninitiated individuals about the whereabouts of the quintessence.
In the Eternal Kingdom, there is no hatred,
For we shall be love.
In the Eternal Kingdom, there is no death,
For we shall be life.
In the Eternal Kingdom, there is no emptiness,
For we shall be the cosmos.
In the Eternal Kingdom, there is no loneliness,
For we all shall be one and the same.
Oh Quintessence, open our eyes to this truth.
...let's break this stained glass and get out of here.
I can't stand this "quintessence" stuff.
A good three whacks, and...
the window shatters.
The liquid doesn't even spill, it just floats in place.
After climbing through, my face meets warm, subterranean air.
All my senses are under constant attack in this cavern.
Most jarringly, hearing.
What causes these reverberations? What is all of this noise?
Do those glowing plants cause it?
Do they also cause this rotten smell?
In the middle of this cavern is this huge pillar.
Near the top, it splits into four.
And then each branch, again, splits into four.
A beautiful coral turning in on itself.
Like that cathedral just now, it's made of that same sickly yellow rock.
I'm all too familiar with it by now.
With the same green growths...
I'm also all too familiar with that stuff by now.
The fissures look somewhat like writing.
Of course, I cannot read it.
I look down. The pillar goes into a lake below.
And then, it burrows even deeper into the ground.
The lake seems to contain the same stuff as everywhere else.
From this high up, the crimson liquid seems to twinkle.
Twinkling like the stars outside.
It's almost inviting.
But I Must Not.
Instead, I look around the rest of the cave.
There are four bridges extending from the pillar.
The center seems as good a place as any to set up camp.
This place is pleasing to the senses.
To Queen of Starlight,
I begged her to never open her eyes again.
Whatever she dreams of is not fit for one so innocent.
Her spasms when asleep...
Her demeanor when awake...
I pray to you, let those dreams be dreams.
No one deserves to suffer through that.
While my daughter has yet the ability to smile, allow her to do so.
I beg of you, Queen of Starlight...
When I first found her, I saw faint starlight in her eyes.
I knew for certain she was the one.
Initially, I chose her for her talent,
but now I can only see someone I have to protect from themselves.
I can only muster so much dedication in a lifetime.
A single pupil is enough to last me until my death.
I hope that she understands that, even if not by blood, she's my child.
And I love her for it.
And now, the time has come for me to choose.
Will I protect my daughter?
Or will I stay true to my creed?
I have always been loyal.
So I beg of you, Queen of Starlight.
Whatever my choice may be.
Whether I become a sinner or a saint...
Please accept my decision with grace.
Signed, a lowly researcher.
To Queen of Starlight,
I've lied to her ever since I knew her.
Yet it was all for her sake.
And for as long as she didn't notice, she was indeed happy.
For thirteen years, she was the happiest girl I had ever seen.
I couldn't have asked for more.
However,
As her mental condition deteriorated, the lies failed to uphold.
Lately, she acted out in rage.
I had to confine her before it was too late.
Rather understandably, she hates me now.
...
My own daughter earnestly wishes for my disappearance.
If it continues like this, it won't be long before the world notices.
I committed acts not worthy of your ears.
The quintessence in her eyes kept on pouring, and so I became overwhelmed with distress.
They had to be shut forever.
...
But even half-blind, she managed to escape.
I reckon this verdict pleases you greatly.
This marks your very own birth, after all.
As for me, I don't think I can continue on any longer.
I've betrayed the one I love;
I've betrayed the one I worship;
and in doing so, I've betrayed myself.
I'll just let her be from now on. Perhaps she will find happiness on her own.
So.
Queen of Starlight, my daughter.
Like this we will part.
I pray for you to one day reach an end,
just as I will soon reach mine.
Signed, ...
A library, in these caves? How exciting.
Where to start, where to start...
"Satvatapatvi"... "Ausrapatvi"...
What use is a great library if I don't know these languages...
Ah, here we go!
Still can't read the title, but...
The shepherd
The dreamer
The wise
The Shepherds of the Stars foresaw it.
The birth of a new King amongst a sea of fakes.
Her name, Soeise, third King of man.
She was raised in peaceful meadows,
and full of love for every sound and every flower;
every insect, every leaf; every tree and every droplet;
every star, every rock; every...
...This seems to go on for a while.
...
So apparently she dreamt herself all the way to the stars.
Whatever that means. And she was the first to do so.
Her dreams started to turn people around her mad.
But despite all that, it's praising her...
fiscal responsibility?
...I'm grabbing another book.
On the horizon, the tower grew tall.
With its end in sight, so came our end in sight.
But born when all hope was lost, a pirate's son.
The fourth King of man, Teonan, raised by bastard thugs.
He had but His mother's flute to take refuge.
But when He had even that taken away,
when father killed mother, He killed all.
Wrought with grief and sorrow,
wrought with a desire to rewind time,
wrought with a feeling of regret,
These books really like repeating themselves.
Okay, quickly going through the rest...
He's sad, he's not sad, he's sad again,
other people find out he's the king,
he has to make some difficult decisions,
and then he's sad again.
...I'm done sifting through these books.
Quintessence.
If only we could understand Its true potential.
Remember your Master's Master?
She advanced our understanding greatly.
We have certainly been able to increase Its purity.
Is your task then not the same? Follow in her footsteps.
Give us an even better view of the Starlight.
You only want that for your own, selfish purposes.
Am I not right?
...
How have you been? It has been a while.
Oh, it's only you.
Have your rotten eyes finally failed you?
I am busy. Do not disturb me.
Cold as ever.
You ignored the League's call.
Are you truly that busy?
Did your Master not raise you properly?
"Devote oneself to the Starlight."
You are a disgrace to our discipline.
Yet you are the one who ignored the League.
No research can justify that.
I can taste the Starlight.
This liquid is truly marvellous.
I can see the stars twinkle.
I see your condition has worsened again.
You really are on the right path. It seems you drew their ire.
I heard they took over the other day?
Ah yes...
The voices managed to break a few bones. Nothing more.
Barely significant compared to those growths on my leg.
Have you tried watering them yet?
Very funny...
...
"One must not cover oneself with quintessence".
This has long been conventional wisdom.
My mind is falling apart, I need this.
I see glimpses of Starlight in my peripheral!
Like my Master's Master! I need this!
It is an inevitability of our research.
But it is always so sad to see a dear friend go.
I will not let those angels stop me.
I am so close to reaching The Inner. Lend me a hand.
Truly unfortunate.
Only a pile of mush remains.
Their study, inaccessible. "Spores".
They did not even leave a disciple behind.
I must thank my Master for her wisdom.
"Do not lose sight of yourself during research."
"If they win, your work will be for naught."
As long as we are careful, we can avoid this.
My voices are only faint.
What a view.
So apparently, the world ends.
Quite quickly, in fact.
Here I am, sitting on the ledge.
Gazing into the void.
Nothing but the purple twilight that's become nostalgic by now.
And the stars... They're so very pretty.
How they pulse, oscillate, fade in, fade out.
To think that they could read these...
Wouldn't it be nice if I could, too?
What was it like, before?
Before I woke up in those floating towers?
I know there probably isn't a "before", but I can dream.
Could the night sky before have been this pretty?
I've been slowly satiating the Eye.
In return, It blesses me with Memories that aren't mine.
Things are gradually falling into place.
Things are starting to make sense, in their own, twisted way.
But I still don't understand.
Why did I wake up here?
Who am I? Why am I?
This one idiom suddenly comes to mind...
The "call of the void"?
I've never heard it before... but it feels right.
There is no "bottom" below my feet here.
Everything just becomes hazy.
Everything just loses definition.
This morbid curiosity of wanting to know what's down there.
Or what isn't down there.
From the empty void, a lukewarm breeze flows through my hair.
Where does it come from?
...
Heh, I should've learnt to stop questioning things like that long ago.
The bugs tried their best, but there's so much they did not teach.
Every time I think I figure something out, this place surprises me again.
But this place, the entire thing, feels a little like a "home", now.
Somehow.
For all of its faults, it really is a beautiful home.
Enough monologuing.
No one here to listen to me babble on anyways.
Let's get moving again.
Yuck, the quintessence in these caves is so much more potent.
▓▒y ▓██▓▒▓▒ you r▓▒▓██▓red ██▓...
The whispers weren't even this strong in that cathedral...
They're creepy.
I guess I should consider myself lucky I don't understand them.
▒▓▓ ▓█e ▓█▓ K███, r▓██▓▒▓▒...
No, not happening.
Why were these guys so obsessed with the stuff?
They seemed to deify it.
From what I could understand, anyway.
So many books I find are decayed beyond belief.
Not to mention all these languages I don't know.
Dri▒k m▒▓e...
Like, the inscriptions on these walls, what do they mean?
I▒'s ▓ ▓█me.
I can't understand you, you dumb liquid.
O█▓ ▓▒ ▓██r▒.
Sigh...
At least I'm not going insane talking to myself, this time...
These tunnels go all over the place...
But there's not a lot here.
G▒ right.
Ew. Be more incomprehensible.
Also, all I can see over there is more quint. Not happening.
▒▓ right.
I only drank just a little, accidentally...
Should've spit it out.
Go In▓██.
No, I'm not going to bathe in you.
That cathedral was plenty.
However creepy the stuff is, though...
It's really pretty how it twinkles.
Especially in the dark, it turns into a night sky.
An alien night sky.
That's t▓▒ ▒▓▓e█.
It's also really easy to ignore.
Well then, if there's nothing here...
Let's just go back to camp.
What's with all this fungus...
That swamp was bad enough,
but here it's covering the entire cavern!
Liken It To Your Immune System.
Covering Everything, We Can Eliminate Any Threat.
Our Vessels May Not Be Harmed.
Then, can You please make it not react to me as well?
Also, can You please stop the "voice coming from everywhere" shtick?
This place is weird enough as-is.
We Are Reacting To You Appropriately.
You're asking me to Remember, but also considering me a threat?
Do You ever start speaking sense?
It Is Not Quite Time To Explain What It Is That You See.
You Shall Not Loiter; Breach The Membrane To Your Left.
achoo
Is breathing in all of these spores even good for me?
I can't help but worry when thinking of those fungi in the swamp.
Worry Not.
As Long As You Follow Our Directions,
Our Spores Will Not Harm Your Body.
Figures.
You Have Also Consumed Some Forbidden Liquid.
Our Spores Are Purifying You Of Its Influence.
You mean the quint-
Do Not Name The Forbidden Liquid.
That sure is a big cocoon over there.
▓▓████▓▒ Is A Not Yet Developed Vessel.
Until It Is Ripe For Harvest, Do Not Draw Near It.
I didn't quite catch that name.
...
No?
Anyways, what is that "vessel" thing inside?
I can only see a silhouette through the membrane, but...
it looks awfully non-human.
And about as gross as everything else here.
We Are Not To Be Disrespected.
Breach The Membrane Straight Ahead.
Traverse The Corridor After With Eyes Closed.
You Will Reach Our Most Developed Vessel.
Look, dear child of mine.
Look how beautiful she's grown up to be!
What... what is this?
What has she become?
She has become whole, has she not?
So was this meant to be?
So the skin of marble, and the cracks upon her face...
So the eyes of ink, and the blood upon her wings...
It was meant to be?
But of course!
All that ceases is destined to return.
Witness, dear child of mine:
Rebirth. The Law of Heaven!
I see...
Do not fret, do not fret.
'Tis what makes us immortal.
I understand.
But...
...
But my daughter, is she still there?
What did you do to my daughter?!
Breathe in, child.
See there, her heart of marble.
She still loves you, child.
And with love, she shall conquer.
But is she not the Harbinger?
Whose sword sheds the blood of nations,
whose voice judges the fate of kings...
Is she not ages-old?
Indeed, she is!
But you yourself, before your birth, were you naught?
Are you not ages-old, too?
I might be...
And have you not killed?
Have you not judged?
That I have...
Do away with your illusions, child.
To love her rightly is to love all of her.
Whether girl or harbinger, innocent or cruel.
I understand, venerable lady.
But I still need some time.
Do as you will.
The Azachon is within you, stand and gaze!
Gaze at what the Heavens have gifted you!
I hate these caves.
They are large, hot, labyrinthine, and worse,
so much more dangerous than those wetlands.
I've only Remembered what, like eight Memories so far?
If only this place was a little more reasonable...
I would've long completed this stupid task.
But I've agreed to it, so for the Eye's sake, I Must Continue.
Not much else to do here, anyway.
...
But I feel like I've found everything these caves have to offer.
There's that river, that cathedral, that thing in the center,
that fungus place, that palace that gives me the creeps...
None lead me further.
Surely I don't have to dig my way down, do I?
Finally...
I've been wandering these caves for ages,
turning every stone like a madman...
Why here, of all places!
Ah, finally something to do again!
Who put these traps in these ruins!
It makes no sense how they still work!
This place looks like it's designed to do one thing, and one thing only:
Kill. Specifically, me.
Moreso than any other place I've been, at least.
Usually the wildlife is the dangerous part...
But here, the floor collapses, I get shot at out of nowhere...
I've even had the ceiling fall on me!
This infernal heat is also something else.
I really can't focus on my surroundings like this.
To think I found those caves too dangerous...
They pale in comparison to this place.
I honestly want to take a break, go back to those wetlands...
and just relax for a moment.
Or perhaps, those gardens. Those are a bit closer by.
(But then I'd need to go through that palace again...)
I do see the beauty of places like this.
Really, I do.
It's just, harder, when they're trying to kill me!
It seems like I've reached the end though.
This door is huge, and...
I Sense Someone Behind It.
Another, normal, living being.
Sigh.
Of course the halfway point is being guarded.
Why wouldn't it be?
I'm ready. Let's go.
What to name our son, milord?
...
He shall be Lord of the Earth,
the lion whose claws shall quench the fires of Hell,
who bestows upon man their wings.
So His name shall be Ariel,
and the Old Earth shall run through His veins.
"Ariel"... Beautiful, milord.
Look at his eyes, aren’t they magical?
Ice-white, like yours once were.
See? All is as told; He is our King.
And you have always been destined to bear Him.
...
The pilgrims are here. The gates shall open.
Sing Him a song, and wear your mask with grace.
Little Ariel, how softly your heart beats...
Your blank little heart, free from desire.
May it remain pure forevermore.
...
I pray you will grow up a better man than your father.
Greetings, wife. How is Ariel?
Come in, dear! Oh how I’ve missed you. How was your time at-
Answer me. How is Ariel?
He walks and he talks, he reads and he writes...
He even reflects on his meditations.
He is growing into a wise prince, milord.
And yet, the curse has not taken him.
He is perfect, milord. And so, so lovely.
Good. But remember:
Do not get attached to Him.
His might far exceeds our own. Do not forget this.
Soon, the young Messiah will join me.
Prepare Him for His travels.
Teach Him the words. Do not disappoint me.
Understood, milord.
Ariel, attend to your studies at once!
No. This is where Mother sat.
She was dreaming, father. And then, you...
How oft must I reiterate!
Enough of this attachment!
The King must ascend above His Kingdom.
"...Ascend above The Kingdom, to cradle it from the clouds", said Teonan.
Silence! Do not talk back at me, Ariel.
Go and reflect on your actions.
Go and reflect on how you slit Mother's throat, father.
...Ariel. I have the League in my reins.
Without the League, you are nothing.
Without your League, I am still the King.
Ariel. Know that half the world wishes you dead.
The League is your sole refuge.
If half the world wishes me dead, then let them kill me.
I’ll become a martyr for the other half.
The whole world shall sing my name toward the pike impaling your head.
You wasteful, manic imbecile.
Thousands of lives lie wasted within your livid mind.
You remember nothing, don’t you?!
I do, father.
"You shall perish of hunger, father."
Shut your mouth!
"And your blood shall stain the desert storms."
I’ll make you a martyr, alright!
"You were a beast, and you shall die as such."
Farewell, father.
So, in the end, it was all a lie.
That's right. But it wasn't all for naught; 'cause I met you.
And with that, all the world's beauty.
Do you hear the seagulls hovering over your head?
And the sun rays shearing over the sea...
And the fresh air breezing through your lungs...
I'm proud to share these feelings with you, false King of Man.
Hey, watch your mouth, you piss-poor horse-herder.
Thank you.
No problem, brother.
Look, Ariel, the sky has opened.
Unbelievable... Shall we stargaze?
And read each other's fates, as did the Kings of old?
Intimate, isn't it? Surely, we too shall fall in love.
You know, Ariel.
In another life, this could've been my journey's end.
It can still be. Join me, Sal.
Join me to the Holy Land, and let's find peace there. Together.
Hmm... What do the stars foretell?
Damned be the stars. Choose your own path!
But the Starlight is my path, Ariel, and you know that.
Burning ambition and maniacal confusion.
That's what I see in your path.
Sounds quite exciting to me. If that's my fate, then so be it.
What a stubborn man you are.
Don’t worry, Ariel.
Our fates may diverge, but this night is ours!
I should have known, by the stars, I should have known!
By the charm in his forever-smile,
by the splendor in his stilted speech,
by the shimmer in his somber eyes...
I should have known!
I loved him, I loved him, I loved him dearly.
That man with a mind serene as the stars,
that man who dreamed to wed himself to life and its beauty.
I should have known, then, that he was still...
that bloodied cripple, who walked the meadows in mania.
Cradling his kingdom from the clouds,
to drown it in its own blood;
he is rotten to the bone.
I hate you, Sal. I hate every single one of you.
Mother, I am hating, forgive me.
My son, I am hating, hear me.
My daughter, I am hating, cleanse me.
My wife, I am hating, stand with me.
...
Azachon almighty, I am hating, come to me.
Azachon almighty, I shall not hate, for I shall fight.
Azachon almighty, hear my prayer!
You've finally made it, prince Ariel.
...greetings, venerable lady.
Oh poor thing, such stillness in your voice.
Have you seen your own eyes? How dejected, how determined.
The journey. What did it cost you?
Everything, venerable lady.
Excellent. I know enough.
You, Ariel, will be my apprentice.
Now bow.
Thank you, venerable lady.
Welcome to our crusade, Ariel.
Death to the King. Death to his Kingdom. Hail the Azachon.
...I do not hate, not forgive; I merely judge...
...I do not think, not feel; I merely observe...
Father, we hear footsteps in the distance.
It has arrived.
...I do not hate, not forgive; I merely judge...
...I do not think, not feel; I merely observe...
My mind is a maelstrom and I See all.
In this moment, I pervade every sensation.
Be it the sensation of my body directing its dance,
or the sensation of my arm bending and bleeding,
or the sensation of my fingers weaving their song,
or the sensation of scorn for the beast before me.
At the apex of obsession, all is one.
This beast shall be slain.
Floors have shattered, the beast is pushing through.
There is not a single emotion upon its disgusting face.
Does there not linger Soeise's compassion,
or Roeroan's rage or Teonan's guilt,
or the beautiful reverence once harbored by Sal?
You are hating, father.
Speak, devil, speak!
I beg of you, speak!
Stop, father, you are hurting, hurting!
Speak to me, brother!
Stop it right now!
Retreat at once! Do it for us!
I must... not...
Merely...
Oh Azachon... almighty...
...
Ah... I have... failed.
What was that bald guy going on about?
Me, a "beast"? A "devil"?
My memories contain nothing warranting such words.
...and these Memories aren't mine to begin with.
...Right?
He also muttered something about the Eye.
I'm simply doing what It requests of me.
Doesn't that mean we're on the same side?
Then why attack me so fiercely?
That fight really brought us down deep, huh.
I cannot even make out the ceiling at this point.
Didn't think ruins could be ruined.
I hope I can still find something under the rubble.
Although, this fight was more informative than any of the Eye's Memories so far.
Perhaps I should ask the Eye about this.
...On second thought, perhaps I should not.
I thought it was because of all the fighting, but...
It's hot down here.
So much hotter than the caverns and ruins above.
Yet, somehow, I don't really feel it.
It feels as if I'm changing the deeper I'm going.
I don't need to sleep any more, either.
My appetite's also disappeared...
But I guess that's all a good thing.
Sleep and meals in a place like this are only a bother.
This gate is humongous.
I really hope that whatever adventure awaits on the other side...
It will be kinder to me than my journey so far.